Setting up a new room for your cat should be fairly straight forward.
If you have cats already, you'll know some of the basic things that they need.
If this is your first cat, then let me go over everything you'll need to have a happy, healthy cat in its own isolation room.
The first thing you'll need is a litter box, you want to make sure it's nice and big, and has a type of litter that the cat is already use to.
This is a non-clumping litter.
If you can find out what your cat has had before its come to you, it will be great to have the same litter that its had all along for it to have an easier transition.
The next thing you want to have, is you want to have a scratching area for your cat, it can be a sisal scratching post or a scratching pad, it doesn't have to be something this big, just something that the cat can have so that it can fulfill its need to scratch things.
Next you want to have some toys in place.
This is a great little bouncy toy, it doesn't take up very much room, and the cat can play with this in all different ways, it can grab it and pull it down or bat it around, and it will give your kitty something to do while it's in its new room.
Also you want to have some kind of a bed for your kitty, a little hammock like this on this condo is great, or you can have a free standing cat bed that has a little bit of a covering so they can really hunker down in there and feel like they're hiding, this will give them a place where they're very safe.
And then once they're allowed to come out into the rest of the house, you can bring this bed out to their favorite spot, they'll already have a place that's familiar to them that they feel safe and comfortable in.